Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/robertscozzari-mba-ml-3307293b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
Staff Development
Team Building
Team Leadership

Languages English

Robert Scozzari MBA/ML

Warehouse and Grain Operations Manager at Onslow Feed and Grain

Richlands, North Carolina, United States

Summary

A dedicated professional with over 30+ years in customer service and program business management. Highly motivated and responsible individual who has exceptional leadership and soft skills to communicate effectively to all levels of management. Seeking a management position where my diverse professional experience and education will allow me to make an immediate contribution as an integral part of the company.

Experience

Onslow Feed and Grain
Warehouse and Grain Operations Manager
February 2020 - Present (3 years 9 months)
Richlands, NC

https://www.onslowfeedandgrain.com/

- Support Owner & General Manager in accomplishing business operations
- Primary responsibility is to establish leadership through integrity & vision
- · Manage the recruiting, interview, & selection process of the work force
- Develop human assets through counseling, training, & personnel development coaching
- Drive value-added operational processes
- Manage the reorganization of warehouse & grain mill operations
- Develop initiative in reducing losses through handling management & inventory practices
- Manage & develop cost, pricing for business operations
- Drive cost analysis ensuring reasonable cost lines
- Benchmark multiple venders to find the best cost solutions
- · Hold venders accountable for product quality
- Liaison with venders ensuring on time resupply
- Managed the product shifts in warehouse & product yard to facilitate the seasonal surges
- · Managed the expiration dates on all product

Analyze financial cost and manage special projects

FORTAY ROOFING & CONSTRUCTION LLC SUB CONTRACTOR (Project Manager)

May 2019 - August 2019 (4 months)

Jacksonville, North Carolina Area

- Work as area manager, focused on providing residents of Eastern, NC roofing solutions
- Recruit and Hire sales personnel
- Recruit sub-contractors with specific job sets
- Negotiate labor prices
- Drive sales through honesty and integrity
- · Work directly with customer on customer satisfaction issues
- Coordinate logistics support for multiple operations simultaneously
- Trained salespeople in developing relationships, and creating a world class customer experience
- · Liaison with venders on coordinating materials quantities and delivery
- · Communicate daily with home office on multiple subjects
- Reconcile with property managers
- · Consolidate sales personnel summaries & submit to home office

Walmart

Fresh Cap II Associate November 2018 - May 2019 (7 months)

United States

- * Provide Clean, Fast, & Friendly Service
- * Zone, Create a neat clean organized area with readable labels
- * Pick, pull, date, & push fresh foods department, using FIFO
- * Customer Availability Program, Scan product in bins ensuring inventory levels are correct
- * Customer Value Program, Price down product with expiring shelf life
- * Claim & Donate product at designated shelf life intervals
- * Operate MC 40 & MC 70 scanners, printers, & scales for production work

Self-Employed

Certified Signing Agent

September 2016 - December 2018 (2 years 4 months)

United States

*Provide counseling on multiple financial issues, time value money, amortizations, interest rate, and personnel budgeting

*Facilitate the lenders and client relations; refinance, reverse mortgages, legal applications, contracts, disclosures, and closing signing services
*Liaison with 22 plus financial institution nationally, law offices, and notary service organizations

Webster University

Veterans Association Work Study (TEMP)
October 2016 - December 2016 (3 months)
Camp Lejeune

Drove awareness through the maximizing of education & recruiting conventions

Initial point of contact agent for prospects entering into student banner system
Assisted Veterans with education benefits & student financial aid
Administration for recruitment of prospect, students, & alumni
Maintain the cleanliness of the office spaces

DICK'S Sporting Goods
Assistant Store Manager / Lodge Sales Manager
November 2014 - July 2016 (1 year 9 months)
Jacksonville, North Carolina Area

Supervise the \$10 million retail operations and Sales of the Hunting, Fishing, and Camping sections of DICK'S Sporting Goods.

- *Drive sales by building customer service and satisfaction
- *Train personnel in company programs to ensure customer satisfaction
- *Drive process and procedures to ensure stock is process in a timely manner
- *Develop procedures to ensure back stock is continuously purged
- *Manage schedule for work section balancing high volume days with light traffic days
- *Open and close store, safe counts, drawer drops, loans, drops, deposit, drawer close and recount
- *Direct the change of the sales floor from season to season
- *Proactive sales manager shifting product on the floor by using Plano-grams along with placement of product in high traffic area to create sales.
- **Created a 6% increase in sale and optimize opportunities putting my section in the top 26 on gun sales in the company and 15% sales for FY 2015.
- **June received a 100% on corporate SAR, 78% in firearms, and received a ATF slap inspection with no findings, and high accolades.

Marine Corps Community Services 2 years 6 months

Supervisor Recreation Specialist (Recreation Shooting) NF-0188-03 May 2014 - November 2014 (7 months)

Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, NC

Primary duties include leading by example while directing and shaping the range facility. Establish a positive work environment through leadership and direction which provides world class customer service. Oversee day-to-day business operations. Ensure compliance with work force regulations and flows. Manage all conflicts effectively working with HR to resolve conflicts. Evaluate procedures to provide optimal and consistent customer service, while developing long range strategic planning utilizing quantitative and strategic business plans. Analyze variances with in multiple budget accounts to stream line cost. Manage supplies and stocks through MRP and spoilage controls. Negotiate with vender to ensure reduced costs to develop retail pricing through use of benchmarking with the goal in creating value to customer.

Recreation Assistant (Skeet, Trap, Archery Range)
June 2012 - April 2014 (1 year 11 months)
Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, NC

Primary duties include leading by example while assisting in the shaping and sustaining of the work environment through leadership and direction with the over goal of ensuring a safe positive atmosphere and culture with in the work section and Semper fit Division. Managerial responsibilities as the lead recreation assistant for section conducted the daily operations & accountability of equipment, retail, and cash inventory while providing worldwide customer service. Coordinate with multiple sections throughout MCCS MCBCL to ensure the smooth operations, and making sure compliance with local directives. Instructor for archery, skeet range, trap range, and five stand creating customer satisfaction.

First Command Financial Services Client Contact Specialist (Intern) January 2011 - March 2011 (3 months)

Performed the duties as a intern for general work force experience and course work. Conducted administrative office work, filling sensitive documents, created correspondence. Job consisted of contacting clients via e-mail / phone, to schedule appointment for multiple Agents. Answer phones / e-mails and took messages, produce, and mail flyers for client seminars.

United States Marine Corps
Operations Chief (MSgt)
May 2005 - July 2008 (3 years 3 months)
Marine Corps Camp Leujene, NC

Primary responsibility of operations chief is to provide guidance to the

commanders and be that link between multiple working companies and customers.

Operations Office Manager # Twelve plus years of progressive program management and leadership. Responsible for the day-to-day execution of large project teams and high priority systems and procedures, managing average of 12 project simultaneously. Established improvement programs designed to increase performance through development of key drivers and metrics resulting in operation cost. Performed as the point person for lean activity for organization. Skilled look outside the box problem solving, creating positive responses to work changes. Responsible for establishing rapid response teams for multiple incidents

Operational Management # assembled and led cross-functional operational planning teams to identifying issues, developing plans, execution, and tracking progress. Developed liaison with customer and adjacent organizations and venders. Developed presentations, executive summaries, and action plans through research and organizing information.

Equipment Account Manager # tracked equipment through life cycles ensuring preventative and corrective maintenance conducted in a timely manner.

Managed Consolidated Material Reports. Analyzed equipment needs in the areas of purchasing, training, maintenance, and infrequent costs estimates.

Training Manager # developed and tracked training plans for 1200 personnel ensuring completion of annual, sustainment, and required certifications renewals. I directed the development of schedules to track training on spreadsheets and databases. Utilized Microsoft office applications, word, excel and Power Point. Ensure conference rooms and media are set up for planning meetings. Directed the focus of training in a multiple company organization

Truck Company HQ BN 2d Mar Div Company GySgt (Administration) June 2002 - May 2005 (3 years) Managed a company of 345 personnel, through ensuring that individual health and welfare were supervised through the establishment of EO policies and incentives that gave personnel a positive reinforcement of support from the chain of command.

Reduced time loss by taking company to the next level of leadership by reestablishing the culture from authoritarianism to individual responsibility. This created a positive effect on the entire company by reducing blotter incidents from 15 to 20 per weeks to an estimated 1 every 6 to 8 weeks.

Redesigned the reporting procedures for training and daily accountability reports that created consistency on one form and alleviated the use of multiple reports to increase accuracy.

Increased the decision making curve by provided incite on problem with personnel or equipment matters while taking the initiative to formulate multiple resolutions for possible action.

Created liaisons with adjacent organizations to establish mutual support relationships that increased availability to assets and skilled personnel in various professions that in turn supported all companies.

Education

Webster University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) with Emphasis in Management and Leadership, Business Administration and Management, General · (2013 - 2017)

University of North Carolina Wilmington

Bachelor of Science Degree, Business Administration · (2010 - 2011)

Coastal Carolina Community College
Associate's Degree, Business Administration (2008 - 2010)

Penn Foster Career School
Certification in wildlife and forestry mangment, Wildlife / Forestry
Conservation · (2007 - 2008)